这个丫头倒很漂亮
This girl looks pretty
她瞪着眼看什么？
Why is she keep staring
这些流浪歌女，两顿也吃不饱
They, wandering singers, could hardly earn their living,
看见了这么多金银珠宝
seeing such a huge treasure
当然会瞪着眼了
no wonder they envy so much
那就对了，我究竟有多少个太太呀？
Well then, how many wives have I got?
一、二、三…应该有二十八个了
One, two, three. . .altogether around twenty-eight
好，那我就娶够二十九个
Very well, I'll make it twenty-nine
报告将军
General!
真的有这种事？
Is this real?
你们不要吵，静一点
Don't argue, stay calm!
大家守规矩呀
Please keep in order
发生什么事？
What happened?
这个月又没有粮饷发了
No salary for this month
又没有粮饷发？
- Again?
是呀
- Yes
发粮饷呀…
Give us the money. . .
他们是不是想造反？
Are they going to start a riot?
不是，已经三个月没发粮饷了
No, they haven't got their salaries for three months
我因为这阵子太忙，所以忘记了
I've been too busy to remember
今天一定会发给他们，叫他们不要吵
Tell them to stay calm, they'll got their money today
出去呀
- Get out!
是
- Yes
将军…是不是准备发粮饷呀？
General, are you going to give them their salaries?
发你的老娘
We've lost our money
我的钱全都输给姓曹的督军了
to General Tsao
那里还有钱发呢？
Where the hell can I have the money?
你马上去通知我所有的太太、儿女们
Go and tell all my wives and children
叫她们准备开溜
to get ready to run
是的，将军
Yes, General!
我们大家准备开溜呀
Well, we all get ready to run
你知道就行了，别大声嚷
Alright, you know it, but don't yell
是，别大声嚷
Yes, no yelling
哎哟！还那么大声嚷
You're yelling even louder
不要吵…
Shut up!
快点呀
Hurry up!
你这么朝烦，别跟着我们了
You're so clumsy, don't join us
巩呀…
Go. . .
这是我的
It's mine
是我的
- It's mine
我也有份呀
- I should've my share
让我拿吧
Let me take it!
勤务兵
Soldiers!
快替我把箱珠宝捡回来
Bring me the jewel box
替我捡才对
Bring to me!
是
Yes!
我一定在做梦了，千万别醒呀
I must be dreaming. Don't wake me up
将军叫妳们马上到后院集合
GN call you...
准备上车
- Get on the car! - Yes. . .
知道了…    要开车了
We get off right away
快点替我捡呀
- Take it for me,
迟了就不等
hurry - Or you'll be left behind
将军，等等我
Wait for me, General
居然穿丝棉？脱下来
How dare you wear silk-cotton? Take it off!
不要醒…千万不要醒过来呀
Don't... Never wake me up!
继续发梦吧，你会捡得更多的
Keep on dreaming, you'll gain more and more
醒了你会后悔的
You'll regret when you wake up
上天你对我太好了
God, you're too good to me!
我发誓，如果我再卖唱过日子的话
I swear, if I ever sing again for my living
我以后就不做人了
I'll be a man no more
车呀…
Car! . . .
我的车不载客的
I take no passenger
谢谢你载我去火车站
Please take me to the railway station
我赶时间乘火车呀
I have to catch a train
姑娘，不顺路呀
But Miss, it's not on my way
你载我到车站去，这条链子也给你
Take me to the station and keep this
那当然行了
Certainly!
那边有很多兵走过来
There's a team of soldiers coming over
到那边看看
Go over there
报告，车子上没有可疑物件
There's no suspicious matter in the car
搜搜那边
Search over there
看什么？
What is it?
站过去，搜身呀
Stand this way!
我身上什么也没有
I've got nothing with me!
别动
Don't move!
看着尸体    是
- You stay here! - Yes
看见什么？
What've you seen?
好像有可疑人物
- Somebody suspicious
可疑人物？
- Suspicious?
回去吧
Go back!
报告督军
Report General!
是不是乱党？
Are there any guerillas?
中枪的人身上，找不到证据
Can't find any proof from the man being shot
督军，你没受惊吧？
Are you alright, General?
我没事
I'm OK!
阿云，妳没受惊吧？
Wan, are you scared?
没什么，爸爸
I'm alright, Papa!
妳在国外这么多年，舒服惯了
You've been away and living in comfort for years
现在回来
now you've to get use to
要适应一下祖国的生活了
the way of living of your native land
我会适应的
I'll certainly make it
报告督军
Commander
姓段的将军因为打朝将的时候
When playing Mah-jong game with you, General Tun
把钱全部输了给你
has lost all the salaries.
现在已经开溜走了
He has already got away
现在士兵正在骚动
The soldiers have started a riot
几副朝将就什么都输给了我
He has lost everything to me only in a few mah-jong games
派人安顿他的下属
send someone to settle his folks down
我们今天马上搬进他的新屋里去
I'll move in his house right away
让我来搜她的身
Let me search him
走开
Stay away!
让我搜她
Let me do it
是
Yes!
她身上没什么
There's nothing
你可以走了
You may go!
走
Go!
站到一边去
Stand aside
春和班，这不就是戏班？
Chun Wo Ban, isn't it a repertory?
听说将军走了
The Commander has gone
这次又不知道派谁来呢？
Don't know who's next?
毛巾
Towel!
春和班
Chun Wo Ban!
机灵点…做人要奋斗
Shape up. . . you've got to fight
老板，药来了
Boss, the medicine's here
快点拿上楼去，快点…
Hurry! Take it upstairs
别担误了，快点呀
No more delay. Hurry!
各位…现在演忠的不够人
Folks...there's not enough actor to play the goods
演奸的快改装演忠的
For those who play the bads should change to play the goods
改装…快点…
Change the costumes... Hurry!
快点…
Hurry up!
妳懂规矩吗？女人不能进戏院的
Do you know regulations? No attendance for women in theatre
我到后台找人也不行吗？
Can I go back stage for someone?
不然也用不着男人扮花旦了
Or...
你们这些男人这么歧视女人
You look down upon on women
真希望有一天，你们全被阉了做相公
you'll be castrated one day
是谁毛手毛脚的，是不是你？
Is that you who've just touched me?
谁摸你呀，我在找鞋子嘛
Hardly, I'm searching my shoes
快点…
- Be quick. . .
师兄呀
- Brother
我的鱼尾纹又多了几条
I've got few more wrinkles
这种纹越数越多的，千万别再去数了
Forget them, the harder you count, the more you'll find
花老板出场
Fa's next
快出场吧，别再玩我了
Go ahead, don't play with me anymore
他真销魂，比昨晚那个姑娘还要漂亮
He's prettier than the girl last night
快点…
Hurry up...
一个跟一个…跟着主角呀
One by one...follow the hero!
不要走错了，快点…
Don't go wrong, hurry...
白妞，怎么是妳呀？
Oh, it's you?
阿爹
Dad,
七岁红昨天晚上起来撒尿着凉了
Kid Hung had a cold
我替他出场…
I take his place...
出妳的老娘
Damn you!
让人家知道我们戏班有女人
Want them to know we've got a dame in the repertory?
我的脸往那儿搁呢？
I'll lose face?
快去把脸洗干净
Go and wash your face
整天想上台做戏，妳能做什么戏？
You always dream to be on stage, what can you act?
想做戏下辈子投胎做男人吧
If you want to perform, recarinate as a man!
行李跟药箱都送回来了
The luggages and the medical kit are back
快点去把脸洗干净
Go and wash your face
进去扎好它
then wrap them up
继续奋斗…
Keep on fighting. . .
女人演女人太平常了，谁会来看呢？
There's nothing special to see a woman plays a female role
妳想呀妳
Only you want
雷大爷，吃过饭没有？
Mr. Liu, did you have your meal?
老板
Boss!
老板，邝查处的人来了
Boss! Some on is coming
处长…请，请
Commissioner, please!
段老板，有没有乱党呀？
Mr. Tun, did you see any guerillas?
我怎么敢有呢？喝茶…
How can I dare to have? Have some tea. . .
喝茶就拿来呀
then bring it over
是，组长
Yes, Captain!
戏班几时来的？
When did the repertory arrive?
昨天才到
Just arrived yesterday
去后台例行检查
Go and search the back stage
北京填鸭
Peking Duck
一鸭三味还是原只上碟？
in three different dishes or the whole duck
这么朝烦，还是生吃吧
So troublesome! Let me have it rare
你是宁北海同志？
Are you Comrade?
你是宋社长
You are Comrade Sung
你要见的人就在我后面
The man that you want to see is standing behind me
我们要找一个方便点的地方
We have to find a more suitable place
我看这个地方比较方便点
I think here is more suitable
对了，没有人
There's no one
别动
Hold it!
你也别动
You also!
干什么？
What?
他是奸细
He's a traitor
我们在搜查乱党
We're looking for guerillas
谁是乱党，自己走出来
Who's guerillas, get out by himself
不要阻误时间了
Don't waste time
她不是我们的人
She doesn't belong here
你怎么知道？
How do you know?
她是督军的女儿
She's General daughter
全北平都知道她是督军的女儿
Everyone in Peking knows that
大惊小怪的，你先看看这封信
Stay calm, read this letter first
我们很辛苦才从外国请曹小姐回来
We invited her from abroad
因为这件事跟她爸爸有关
As this matter has connection with her dad
你千万别暴露曹小姐的身份
Don't expose her identity
否则就前功尽废了
If not, we can't succeed
有一个女人，锁起她
There's a woman, knock her up!
这次机密行动跟袁大总统有关
This mission is about President Yuen
跟袁世凯有关？
President Yuen?
我们一定要偷一份文件
We've to steal a document
什么文件？
What document?
我们怀疑他向外国银行秘密借钱
We suspect he loans money from foreign bank secretly
向外国人借钱？
Loan money from foreigner?
他是想巩固军力，对抗南方国民政府
He wants to build up his power to conqueror the South
恢复帝制
Back to monarchism
那为什么要找你？
Why me then?
我们怀疑
We suspect
我爸爸是袁世凯向银行借钱的经手人
My dad is the middle agent for the progress
也就是说文件在他那儿
And the document is with him
我们一定要得到手
We've to have that paper
好让国会揭发袁世凯的阴谋
So we can discover Yuen's conspiracy
我们才有真正的民主政制
Then we can have democracy
什么事呀？
What's the matter?
我在你的戏班里
I'm here
她是我的女儿
She's my daughter
这么伤风化的事你也敢做
Doing such immoral thing
你怎么证明她是你的女儿
How can you prove she is your daughter
是我老婆生的嘛
Her mother is my wife
快点去找证明呀
Give me proof
行…我马上去找我老婆来
Okay...then
写清楚点，不然那些老倌又发脾气了
Write carefully, if not, they'll lose their temper
不得了罢…快把今天的台金给我救人
Give me money to save a man
全部给你，好严重的事
- That's it! A serious matter
对呀
- Yes
我老婆来了
My wife's coming
班主，你又在招摇撞骗了
You're cheating
又怎能养出这样大的女儿呢？
How...?
改天我找一个肥一点的来做证明
Show be a fat one tomorrow
这才像话嘛，外面在演什么戏？
What are you performing outside?
霸王硬上弓
The Stuber King
霸王硬上弓，这么好的戏
A good one
我们要出去欣间
We want to watch
就会说女人是乱党
All women are guerillas,
怎么又不抓你妈呢？
how about your mom?
妳还说…死丫头
How dare you say that?
快把裤子脱下来还给七岁红
Take off the pants & give back to Kid Hung
出去做饭
Prepare supper!
我们今晚是不是吃火锅呀？
We're having sukiyaki tonight?
吃火锅？吃番薯
Sukiyaki? Potato!
走开
- Go away!
识相点
- Be smart!
外面邝查处的人来了，他们无孔不入
He's from Ticketing Office, they're everywhere
以后要小心点
Be careful next time
记着
Remember,
我们以后在宋社长的出版社联络
we'll meet at Sung's office
我偷到文件之后，你带回南方去
After I steal the document, you take it down to South
不错呀
- No bad,
比隔壁的那个相公还要漂亮
- prettier than the guy next door
叫什么名字？
What's his name?
花锦绣
Fa!
阿爹，你还没给钱我买菜呢
Dad, you haven't money for supper
昨天吃剩的番薯呢？
Where is the potato of last night?
怎么够饱呢？
Did you have enough?
就知道吃，小心我打断妳的腿
Know eating only. Beware I'll break your leg
班主，你又寻花问柳呀？
Courting again?
是呀，你要召妓吗？
Don't pretend
用不着这么文绉绉的
as a gentleman
阿爹，要不要等你回来？
Dad, need me to wait for you?
要不要等？叫妳看门口干什么？
Otherwise I won't ask you to stay?
小心我扭掉妳的耳朵
I'll cut your ear
你干什么？
What are you doing?
好漂亮的洋车呀
Pretty car
大哥，那小子怎么办？
What are going to do to that guy?
哪些珠宝哪儿去了？
Where is the jewelry?
老兄，我真的没有拿过    真的？
- I didn't take it - Really?
绑起来，带他回去
Tide him up
不说就阉了他
If he didn't say it, castrate him
有没有别的刑罚呀？
Did you have another punishment?
督军呢？
Where's General?
他在书房跟外国人开会
He's having a meeting with foreigner
小姐，早点休息罢
Miss, have a rest first
行了，你出去吧
OK, get out
是
Yes!
双方是要保证履行合约的
Guanatee too do according to the contract
如果我国有违返合约的条款
If we fail to do so
五间外国银行有权没收所有的抵押品
Then the 5 foreign banks have the right to take everything as penalty
行…你再说一遍
Repeat what you said
大总统可以拿到多少钱？
How much can the President get?
借款是二千五百万镑
The loan is 25,000,000 pounds
而大总统实收是这笔钱的三份之一
So he can have 1/3 of it
而四十七年之后
And 47 years later
我国还款是六千七百五十万镑
We'll pay you back 67,500,000 pounds
相等于借款的三倍
That's 3 times of the loan
四十七年后的世界是怎么样的
What will the world looks like 47 years later
有谁会知道
Who knows?
拿笔来，让我签名
Give me a pen for signature
过两天就把文件交给大总统过目
I'll show President the contract in 2 days
应该不会有问题
There shouldn't be any problems
他们干什么？
What are they doing?
他们举杯向督军致敬呀
They're tossing for the President
好！做得好
Great...
告诉他们，我今天请大家吃晚饭
Tell them, I invite them for dinner
请大家到大厅等我
Wait me at the living room
是
Yes!
排长
Captain!
别动
- Hold it!
谁？
- Who's that?
是妳？
Is you?
怎么是你？
How come is you?
没有我的命令，就私自行动
Taking action without my order
你太鲁莽了
You're too rough
别多说了，快去拿文件吧
Don't bullshit, go and get the document
你真不小心，快把东西拾起来
Careless. Pack up the thing
怎么会是妳？
How come is you?
是自己人？
Were in a group
应该不是
Shouldn't be
北京填鸭
Peking Buck!
蛮好吃的
Taste good
她不是自己人
She's not our men
什么事？
What's the matter?
有枪声，大家到处查看一下
I heard a shot
里边又有朝烦
Problems inside
我们又可以趁火打劫了
We'll get rich
大哥，这小子怎办？
How about this guy?
别浪费时间，带他一起去吧
Don't waste time. Bring him along
是不是有枪声？
- Is there a fire out there?
是
- Yes
叫副官去看看
- Check it up
是
- Yes!
不好了，有脚步声，改天再找机会吧
Someone is coming. Find another chance another day
小姐
Madame!
那边有个人影闪过，快追
I saw someone over there
是
Yes!
惊动了守卫，你大概是脱不了身
You can't run away
想办法到车房去等我
Wait me at the garage
我先回书房去
I'll go to study room
督军
General!
等等，你想到哪儿去？
Wait, where are you going?
跟着上来保护我
Protect me
是
Yes!
好高呀
It's too high!
开门    是
Open the door. Yes!
在书房里，快点
In the reading room, quick!
快点
Quick!
督军，是不是有枪声？
General, is it a gun shot?
为什么现在才来？
Why are you so late?
里边有乱党，进去搜
There're guerillas inside, search!
你们听着，里边有乱党
You listen, there're guerillas inside
进去搜
- Go in and search!
是
- Yes
这个是乱党呀
This is the guerilla!
追，快点追
After him, quick!
你们俩保护督军
You two protect the General
听着，任何人不许进出
Listen, no one goes out or comes in
否则格杀勿顶
Or shoots him down
是
Yes!
他走了？
He's gone?
那我也要走了
Then I have to go!
满屋子都是兵，妳是想被人抓住？
The house is full of soldiers, you want to be caught?
那妳还想不想走呢？
Do you still want to go?
坐下
Sit down!
妳坦白的告诉我
You tell me the truth
妳来这里的目的是什么？
What is your mission in here?
什么叫做目的？
What is mission?
目的也不懂，妳为什么要来这里呢？
You don't know mission? Why do you come here?
我自己也不知道
I don't know myself
我跳进木桶里边
I jump into the bucket
是木桶带我到这里来的
It's the bucket brought me here
这算不算是目的呢？算不算呢？
Is that a mission? Is it?
我救过你一次，妳一定要答应我
I've saved you once, you must promise me
今晚的事，妳不可以告诉任何人
What happens tonight, you won't tell anyone
这个我会的，我可以发誓
I will, I can swear
用不着这么朝烦了
You don't have to do that
不朝烦，我经常发誓的
No trouble at all, I always swear
跳过去
Jump over!
这么高，我好怕呀
It's too high, I'm afraid
妳怕高还是怕死？
Are you fear of height or fear of dying?
怕死
Dying!
那快点跳呀
Then jump now!
大哥，洋车呀
Brother, a motor car!
你看，那两个车头灯亮晶晶，多美啊
Look, the head-light is shinning, how beautiful
一定很值钱的
It must be pretty expensive
趁现在没有人注意，我们搬走它
Nobody's watching, let's move it away
好
- Good!
快点，来
- Quick, come!
你们连督军的车子也想…
Don't you know it's the General's car...
帮手推车是吗？
Give us a hand?
快点
- Quick!
来了
- Come!
拿到天津去卖了它，我就发财了
Take it to Tinjuin and sale it, then I'm rich
排长呀
Captain!
求求你呀排长
I beg you Captain,
千万不要说在这里看见我
please don't tell anyone you see me here
不能走
Stay here!
如果事情传出去
If the thing gets spread out
我们以后再也不能趁火打劫了
We can never rob in this way again
不如我们杀了他吧
How about we kill him!
如果被督军知道了
If the General knows about it,
他一定会枪毙我的
he will shoot me
求求你排长，求求你不要告诉…
I beg you, Captain, please don't tell...
你们干什么？
What are you doing?
你们不要呀
You guys don't
上
Go!
你不要这么猖狂呀
Don't be so ruthless!
不要杀他呀
Don't kill him!
怎么会这样呢？
Why is it like this?
被那王八蛋发现我了
We've been discovered by those bastards
别多说了，快把门关上
Say no more, close the door!
妳为什么带着她走呢？
Why do you take her along?
她糊里糊涂的来了
She came here by accident
我们就糊里糊涂的带她走
Then we are going to take her by accident
如果被人抓住了
If we are caught
她一定会把我们的秘密说出来的
Then she will take all our secret
好吧
OK!
救我呀，我不想死
Help me, I don't want to die
他还没死？
He's not dead?!
你干什么？
What're you doing?
他救过我，我不可以不理他呀
He has saved me, I can't leave him like that
人越来越多，快上车吧
It's getting crowdy, get in!
我们在哪里见过面？
Have we met somewhere before?
你受了重伤，眼花了
You hurt real bad, you are getting dizzy
快把伤口盖起来
Cover up the wound, quick
大小姐
Madam!
还不开闸？
- Open the gate
是
- Yes!
开闸
Open it!
油箱穿了，车子不能走
The oil-tank has a hole, the car can't move!
妳听，好像有人来呀
Listen, someone is coming!
邝查处的人
It's from the Ticketing Office
给他们看见我们这样，会很朝烦的
If they see us like this, we are in trouble
那我们把车子留下
May be we leave the car
带他们俩去个安全的地方
Take them two to a safe place
否则会更朝烦的
Or there will be more trouble
流这么多血，我看见血会晕的
So much blood, I will faint
扶着他
Hold him!
我的裙子呀…
Oh my dress! . . .
不好了，给他看见了
Damn, they've seen us
你不要带着他一起走
Don't take him with you
阿爹
Dad!
喂，你们是什么人呀？
Hey, who are you guys?
进来干什么？
What are you doing here?
原来想避开那些王八蛋
So you want to get away from these bastards
不错，姑娘，所以妳要帮我们的忙
Right, lady, that's why you got to help us
不好了，他伤得这么重
My god, he hurts so bad
要马上施手术呀
He needs an operation
找个地方先安顿他
- Find a place for him first
施手术？
- Operation?
我到车上去拿手术用具
I'll go to the car to get the tools
你先扶他进去
You first take him in
我马上扶他进去
I'll take him in
那边不能去，到我的房间去吧
Can't go there, go to my room!
我不能够随便开门让人家进来的
I can't open the door and let everyone in
好，我们的暗号是北京填鸭，妳记着
OK, our code is Peking Duck, you remember!
北京填鸭
Peking Duck?
我马上回来
I'll come back immediately!
这个更夸张
This is even more ridiculous
妳在这里乱嘲，嘲什么呀？
You've been searching all around, what are you looking for?
请问放在车上的箱子在哪里呀？
Do you know where's the box in the car?
在后台
Back-stage!
后台在哪里呀？
- Where is the back-stage?
那一边
- Over there!
我自己去
I'll find it!
回来，不许乱跑
Come back, no running around!
姑娘，有没有干布？
Girl, do you have a piece of cloth?
拿一块替他擦血
Take one and clean the blood for me
走吧！浑蛋！
Get away! Bastard!
叫你的下友不要乱跑好不好？
Tell your friend not to run around, will you?
我不认识她
I don't know her
不认识？
Don't know her?
不认识你们俩怎么会在一起呀？
Don't know her then why are you together?
好奇怪吗，我也不认识他
Is that strange, I don't know him either
什么？
What?
出去那个女人你们认不认识呀？
Do you know the woman who went out?
认识
- I know her - I know
我真不知道你们玩什么把戏
I really don't know what kind of game are you playing
我去开门
I'll open the door
不用了，你们两个看住她
Don't bother, you two watch her
北京填鸭
Peking Duck!
北京填鸭…
Peking Duck...
宫保鸡丁呀
It's Tuna Fish!
错了，你走吧
Wrong, go away!
快来开门，我是妳爹呀
Open the door, I'm your dad!
臭丫头，快开门
Bitch, open it!
阿爹，对不起呀
Sorry!
小心我扭掉妳的耳朵，鸭…
Watch out or I'll tear your ear off
阿爹
Dad!
妳肚子很饿吗？就顾着吃
Are you that hungry? Always think of food
鸭妳的头
Duck your head
怎么打呵欠好像喊救命似的？
Why yawn as you are calling for help?
我好累呀
- I'm too tired! - Just go to sleep
快去睡觉，去睡吧…
Go to sleep...
死了，我爹回来了，你们快点走吧
Damn, my dad is back, you must go!
不好了，这次又是谁呀？
Oh no, who is it this time?
我死定了
I'm dead for sure
不行，我一定要赶他们走的
No, I must send them away
北京填鸭还是宫保鸡丁呀
Peking Duck or Tuan Fish!
北京填鸭
Peking Duck!
对了
Right!
怎么会有宫保鸡丁的？
How came there is Tuan Fish?
北京填鸭是你们
Peking Duck is yours
宫保鸡丁是我爹，他已经回来了
Tuna Fish is my father, he's already back
我两只耳朵又要受苦了
My ears are going to be tortured again
你们还是快点走吧
You better be going!
拿烧酒跟白布来
- Take the wine and the cloth here
好
- OK
顺便烧一锅热水
- And heat some water
好
- Yes
我不是要赶他们走的吗？
Shouldn't I send them away?
先把他的衣服撕开
First tear off his clothes
拿块干布来擦血
Take the cloth and wipe off the blood
妳还站在这里干什么？
Why are you still standing here?
还不快去拿东西
Go get the thing
好了，现在他没事了
OK, he is alright now!
这里地方太小了，你先扶她出去
It's too crowdy here, you take him out first
还嫌地方太小，真气死人了
And you think the place is too crowdy, I'm going to blow up
坐下
Sit down!
妳在外国念医科的？
You study medicine oversea?
我是念妇科的
I study gynaecology
现在可以去后台了
I can go to back stage now.
真是的，连拿个灯笼也没力气
Really, you can't even hold
晚上早点睡觉，就连皮肤也漂亮点
Go to bad earlier, even your skin will be more beautiful
我那瓶花露水呢，快还我
Where is my perfume, give me back
知道了，小器鬼
I know, stupid!
不好了，那些花旦吃完番薯回来了
Oh no, those actress are coming back
趁现在没人看见，你们快点走吧
Before anyone sees you, you better leave!
走呀
Go!
快点走呀
Go, be quick!
还有个丫角髻呢？
Where is the chignon?
那些花旦回来了，走呀…
Those actress are coming, go. . .
你看看这只看门狗
You look at this watchdog
她还在笑呢
- She's still laughing
去你的
- Damn you!
真讨厌
I hate this!
爸爸，你还没睡呀？
Dad, you've not sleep yet?
今天晚上家里发生这么多事
There's problems raise up tonight
妳叫我怎么睡得着呢？
How can I sleep?
我想起妳妈那天晚上的情形
I thought about that night
跟今晚差不多
It was exactly the same as tonight
她为了救我，替我挡了一枪
She saved my life
否则，我早就没命当督军了
If not, I'll not be alive
这枝枪，是一个法国人送给我的
This pistol is a gift from a French
现在妳爸爸身边太危险了
It's a dangerous around here
妳拿去防身吧
Take it with you!
爸爸，我会照顾我自己的
Dad, I'll take care myself
这枝枪，你留着自己防身吧
Keep it with you
爸爸身边有很多警卫
I've guards
我就是怕妳到处走，有危险
I'm worrying about you
爸爸没有儿子，只有妳一个女儿
You are my only child
我担心我这么多年来
I worry there's no one
打回来的江山没有人接手
to inherit my country
爸爸打仗，打到头发也白了
I'm old
什么也看透了
I see everything already
妳要记着，一个人最重是为自己
Remember, do anything for your ownself
爸爸
Dad!
要是禽了这条钥匙
If I lose this key
我们就要从头再做起
We've to start from the beginning
牛耕田，马吃谷
Work like a dog
老爸赚钱儿享福
For this children
千万不要把爸爸的话当耳边风
Pay attention to what I said
爸爸今晚有人陪，妳早点睡吧
I've a companion, go to bed!
督军
General!
现在我爸爸把那条钥匙放在身边
Dad keeps the key with him
我们要去偷钥匙，又要去开保险箱
If we've to steal the key, and open the safe
这样走来走去的
At the same time
在时间上好容易给他发觉的
It'll be to obvious
妳说的对
You're right!
除非我们把钥匙偷出来印个模
Unless we make a mode for the key
然后第一时间还给他
Then give back the key instantly
不就行了
That's be well
我爸爸他很风流
My dad has a woman
每天晚上都要女人陪的
with him each night
我怕让那个女人发觉了
That woman will notice
他洗澡的时候，不就只有他一个人吗
Is he alone when he's bathing?
浴室没有地方可以藏身
Nowhere can hide in the bathroom
那我们不是束手无策吗？
What else can we do?
我可以发表我的浅见吗？
Can I make a little suggestion?
为什么他会在这里的？
Why is he here?
如果到处走，很容易被人发现
It's so easy to be caught running around
躲在这里比较安全点
It's safer to stay here?
不要再讨顶了，好不好？
Can you stop arguing?
先听听我的浅见吧
Listen to my suggestion first!
好，你发言吧
OK
你说睡房，他说浴室
You said the bedroom & you, the bathroom
为什么不利用茅厕呢？
Why not the toilet?
茅厕
Toilet!
当督军离开大帅府
When the General leaves his house
人急起来，当然要去茅厕啰
Everyone has that necessity
如果你有办法让他进这间茅厕
If you can make him to go to the toilet
而你又在这间茅厕里等他
And you wait him there
那他不是自动送上门了吗？
Then he's trapped
浅见说完了，我进去罢
I finish
如果我们真的没别的办法
If you've no other way
这个办法也行得通
We can try this one
真的去茅厕吗？
Really the toilet?
哪一个茅厕？
Which one?
我也在考虑呢
I'm thinking!
广和楼
Kwok Wo Building!
汪老板，他们是天津请回来的花旦
Mr Wong, they are the actors from Tinjuin
好…带他们去见花老板
Show them to Fa
这边…
This way...
准备家伙，今晚演穆桂英招亲
Have everything ready
是
Yes!
快去呀，快
Go!
妳还去搞什么？快去呀
What are you doing? Come down!
妳看见什么就做什么
Do anything you see
反正有事就做，快去吧
Just work
快去
Quick!
用不着扮神秘了
Don't pretend to be miserious
珠宝…快点出来呀
Pearl...come out!
在那边
That way
上面包厢，在那边
The box is up there
钱禽了
I lost my money
怎么连根柱子也要擦呀
Why are rubbing the stand
差点连座位也没有了
Almost full
走开点…我们有喜事…
Get away...we're celebrating
有喜事就了不起吗？
Big real?
走开呀，别零事
Get away
我们有喜事，走开…
Get away. . .
喜事
Celebrating
你们快派人出来取礼呀
Ask your men to come for present
放在这里，放下
Put it down!
别乱摸呀
- Don't touch
什么事？
- What's the matter?
叫你别动的，信不信我抓你呀
Don't move, I catch you at last
送礼给谁的…
Who are you send the present to?
我们奉了雷组长命令
With Commander Liu's order
送礼物给花锦绣，花老板的
Send these to Fa
谁找我呀？
Who is looking for me?
有人送礼物给你呀
Someone is sending these to you
就是嘛，一个人走起运来了
When you are in good luck
什么事都顺意的
Everything goes smooth
就连做官的也要哄我开心呀
Even the council will take notice of you
对，我们组长好想你开心
Right, our Commander wants you happy
你收了礼物后
After you have these
三天后我们就用花轿来接你回来
He'll pick you up in 3 days
以后，你就安安份份的做他相公
Then you'll be his husband
我是男人呀，怎么做相公呢？
But I'm a man
他不想做相公呀
He doesn't want to
就是男人才可以做相公
That's it
我不做相公…你去找他们吧
I don't want to. . . go for someone else
你做不做？
- You do it?
你不要毛手毛脚的
- Don't touch me!
传了出去
If it spread out,
我还能生儿育女，继后香灯？
I couldn't get married
我怎么可以为了你
I can't
牺牲我一生的幸福呀
Sacrifice for you
那你过不过门？
Are you going to get married to commander?
不过
No!
打
Beat him!
你有自由选择的权利
You cab your choice
你不是说我可以自由选择吗？
You say that
做人一定要开心
Have to be happy
勉强是不会有幸福的
Can't by force
大爷，他的皮肤好嫩，一擦就破了
His skin is so soft
还有，女人是要哄的，不是要打的
Woman needs soothing
你看看你自己，也真的是
Look at yourself
天生一双桃花眼，到处勾勾搭搭
Flirting around
也真是活该
Too bad
现在雷家的礼物来到了
Liu's present is here
你就不该再多心，爱情专一点
Don't flirt anymore
牺牲小我，为戏班着想
Sacrifice yourself for the repertory
三天后过门
Get married in 3 days
大家四周检查一下
Search around
亲爱的
My dear
你不会想像得到将来是怎样幸福的
Think of your comfortable lives afterward
督军来看戏了
General's here
督军他来看戏？
He's here because of me?
督军他来看戏，要是没有花老板
If Fa is not with us
我们就没戏可唱了
We'll be finished
别在督军面前抛媚眼
Don't do that in front of General
督军
General!
师叔
Master!
白妞，妳要救我呀
Pat Nell, you've to save me
卑职是邝查处第六组组长雷止雨
I'm the Ticketing Officer Mr. Liu
是来保护督军看戏的
Coming to protect the General
师叔，你想逃走呀？
Are you trying to escape?
你要到哪里去？
Where are you going?
我去济南，必要时跑跑龙套
Being a dumb in Chainam
就算到乡村去演戏也要去
We've to even act in small town
妳做什么？
What are you doing?
下乡班很穷的，你多带几套戏服吧
Take more costume with you
将来会有用的
You can make use of it
妳出台替师叔演完这场戏
Take my place
不要被人发现我逃走了
Don't let anyone see me running away
外面风风雨雨，你只得一个人
You're alone
多带点药吧，万一有病也可以应急呀
Take some medicine with you
走快点，班主催场了
Run
走快点呀
Run!
或者我们没机会再见了，妳要保重呀
May be we won't see again! Take care!
师叔，你路上要小心
Take care!
快点化妆呀
Put on the make up
这些点心督军不喜欢吃的
The General doesn't like this kind of food
换过这些上来吧
Change it
这些点心我最爱吃的
I like this dimsum
她是谁？
Who is she?
是你的女儿
Your daughter
我的脸都给她禽光了
She makes me lose face
去看看花锦绣哪儿去了？
Look for Fa?
是
Yes!
督军
General!
这个是谁？
- Who is she?
不知道
- I don't know
还好，那不是更禽脸了
That's better
在后台找不到花锦绣
I can't find Fa back-stage
什么？不见了
What? He's gone!
到处搜搜，不要让他跑了
Don't let him go away
是
Yes!
她是假的，我是真
She's fake,
I'm real
我也收兵了
Let's go
追
Chase!
快点呀…
Quick. . .
这边人多，我到那边去
I go over that side
不好了，走错位
Wrong position
老实说，我现在怎办？
What am I going to do?
跟着我做
Follow me
我怎么做，妳怎么做
Do what I do?
督军，我肚子好饿呀，督军
General, I'm hungry
肚子饿就吃了它
Take a bite then
大小姐，妳脸色不大好，没事吧？
Miss, are you alright?
我没有，看戏吧
I'm fine
叫她们回来后台受斩呀
Take them back-stage
上方宝剑，有什么问题，先斩后奏
No need to explain
领旨
Yes Sir!
我被刺中了，我快死了
I'm hurt
你不能死，死了就没薪水了
You can't die,
拔不出呀
you haven't paid us yet
如果他们是女人
If they are women
我就娶他们回来做姨太太
They can become my wives
老板，我是死还是不死呀？
Boss, shall I die or not?
你这么喜欢死，你以后便做死尸吧
Since you like it so much, stay dead
做死尸用不着化妆
No need to put on make up disguising as a corpse
以后我们可以多打些牌
We can get closer afterwards
督军，我肚子痛呀
General, I've a stomach ache
去茅厕吧
Go to the toilet then
那怎么办？
What are we going to do?
押下去
- Take him away - Yes, Sir!
遵命
一字马，好辛苦呀
That's difficult
他是谁呀？
- Who is he?
好痛呀
- So painful!
想揩油呀
Taking advantage!
都是女人呀，我怎么见人呢？
We're women, what am I going to now?
雷组长
Commander Liu!
大小姐，有什么事？
What's the matter, Miss?
厕所在哪里？
Where's the toilet?
那边，我带妳去吧
This way, I'll show you
不用了
No, thanks!
你在这里保护督军，我自己去行了
I can find my way, you say here to protect General
北海
Pak Hoi!
我在这里
I'm here
你们两个保护大小姐去方便
You two go to protect Miss
顺便看看狂姑娘
By the way find out
为什么这么久还不回来
why Miss Choi is late?
怎么会搞成这样？
What's happening?
她给我吓晕了
Because of me
狂姑娘
Miss Choi!
狂姑娘在里边晕倒了
Miss Choi passed out
快点扶她出来
Take her out
是
Yes!
扶她过去
- Here!
是
- Yes
什么事？
What happened?
鬼，厕所有鬼呀
A ghost, in the toilet!
鬼？什么鬼呀？
Ghost?
不是鬼，是花锦绣
Not ghost, is Fa
保护督军
Protect the General
胁持我
Threaten me?
别动
Hold it!
乱党，抓住他
Grab the guerillas
别动！起来
Freeze! Get up!
小心后面呀
Beware!
快蹲下
Lie down!
我的箱子呀
Oh my box!
往这边走
This way!
我的箱子呀
Oh my box!
你飞得真好看呀
You flew excellent
可惜你不是一只鸟
Too bad you're not a bird
始终会掉在我手掌里的
But you'll be in my hand
让我用只笼来罩着你
And keep in my cage
慢慢的教你飞吧
And teach you to fly!
放了他…
Release him! . . .
不然我就一枪打死督军
If not, I'll give General a shot
打死穿黑衣服的那个
Shot the guy in black
他好坏的
He's bad
不行，他挟持着我爸爸
No, he's my dad as the hostage
那这两枝枪千万不能走火呀
Hope these pistol wouldn't run out fire
你只有一粒子弹
I only have one bullet
打死了督军，你自己能跑得了吗？
You can't escape after shooting General?
走过去…我不管，交换人质
I don't care, exchange hostage
走过去，走过去呀
Go there!
抓住他，不要开枪
Grab him, don't shoot
不要开枪…小心我呀…
Look at me!
别动呀
Hold it!
你算是什么？开枪
Who do you think you are! Fire!
他开枪呀，他不当我是人
Don't, he doesn't think I'm a human
想不到我还可以跳得这么高
I did expect I can jump that high
戏院里有乱党，全部抓回去
There's guerillas in the theatre
组长，乱党来了，收下吧
The guerillas's coming, take them
那就不抓人，戏院照封
Close down the theatre
封戏院？
Close down the theatre?
阿爹
Dad!
我早叫妳不要上台的
I told you not to go on stage
妳这死丫头，我打死妳
You bitch, I'll kill you!
站着
Stand still!
我们走
Run!
走到哪儿去？
To where?
不要拉着我，我要打死她
I've to kill her
不要呀…
Don't...
我叫了妳不要上台，妳偏要上台
I told not to go on stage, but you did
我打死妳
I've to kill you
不要拉着我…
Don't hold me...
妳呀，妳害得戏院被封了
The theatre is closing down
戏又没得唱，你还留在这里干什么
Why are staying here for?
爸爸，我留下了点东西在后台
Dad, I left my thing in the back-stage
你先回家去吧
Go home first!
副官，保护小姐
Protect Miss
是
Yes!
找到了
Found it!
天气冷，快披上衣服吧
It cold outside, put on a coat
我不用妳可怜我
I don't need your sympathy
刚才妳表演得很精已
Your performance was terrific
精已又有什么用？
What for?
女人上台表演，替戏班禽脸
A woman performs on stage
只会给人取笑
Everyone will laugh at her
别傻了
Don't be silly,
刚才妳没听见台下那么多掌声吗？
did you see the acclaims?
妳表演的身手这么棒，千万别灰心
Don't get depress, you're excellent
就算失败了，可以从头再来呀
Even you fail, try again
妳千万不要放弃
Don't get loose
真禽我们的脸呀
Make us lose face!
来呀…过来呀，一起披着
Come here!
来…快点呀
Quick. . .
对了，我们去喝酒吧
Let's go for a drink
好呀
OK!
这些衣服是我留学时穿的
These clothes I used to wear abroad
怎么念过书的女孩子
How come all educated girls
平时穿的衣服也这么古古怪怪的
Dress up so funny
有时候分不出是男是女
Can't tell if a buy or a girl
办起事来会方便很多的
To move more freely
团团转的，是什么东西？
What is this?
这是地瞴鹤
This is the scope
什么鹤？
What?
这是我们住的世界
This is our world
这里就是中国
This is China
妳看
Look!
北平在哪儿？
Where is Peking?
像一粒米那里就是了
Here, as a dot
那广和楼呢？
Where is Kwok Wo Building?
全在这粒米里边
Inside the dot
妳不是说笑吧，怎么看不见房子的？
Are you kidding, there's no houses?
北平好像一粒米
Peking looks like a dot
世界那么大，我能跑到哪儿去？
The world is so big, where can I go?
妳想到别的地方去？
Are you planning to go somewhere?
人人都说要走，也不少我一个了
Everyone is running away
逃亡嘛
Run for life
我真不明白，这里不是很好吗？
I don't get it, this is a nice place?
为什么还要到处去呢，对不对？
Why have to run away?
有时候我们走来走去
We're running around
结果还是走回头
And finally we go back the same route
爸爸
Dad!
你还没睡呀？
Did you sleep?
没有
Not yet!
她们是我的下友
They're my friend
我现在送她们回去
I'm sending them home
这么晚了，就留下来住一晚吧
They can stay for a night
不，我很快就会回来的
I'll be back soon
来，快点呀
Quick!
副官，是什么人？
Who is it?
她们就是今天台上的那两个刀马旦
They were the actors on stage today
她们原来是女人？
They are women?
你看
Look!
你们俩怎么会在这里？
How come you are here?
出版社被人监视了
The Publishing Office is being watched
社长叫我们今晚不要回去了
Officer told us not to go back there tonight
对
Right,
所以我们俩今晚要找个地方躲一躲
we need a place to hide up
冷死人了
So cold
只有一张床，一张被
Got only one bed & one blanket
怎么睡呀？
How can we sleep?
不要紧，大家都是女孩子
Doesn't matter, we're all girls
一起睡好了
We can sleep together
来吧，快点罢
Come on!
不是说一起盖被的嘛
We can share the blanket
睡吧
Sleep
你来呀    没有位，不好靠过来
Come On! No seat here, don't come near
老板…
Boss...
什么事呀？
What's the matter?
督军命令，戏院一定要重开
The General ordered to reopen the theatre
他今天晚上来看戏
He's coming tonight
你快去找你女儿
Look for your daughter
跟昨晚那个女孩子回来
and that girl
为什么？
Why?
不然就死定了
If not, you'll die
快点
Quick!
白妞…
Pat Neil. . .
怎么妳在这里也不答我一声
How come you didn't answer me
怎么了？不舒服？
What? Are feeling alright?
是不是发烧，脸都红了
Are you having a fever?
不是，我发冷呀
No, I'd a cold
发冷就盖被嘛，发冷
If you'd a cold
真是的
Really!
其实阿爹常常打妳、骂妳
Dad hits you
也是为了妳好
is for your good sake
妳不用怕
Don't scare
妳看看妳，做活做得手也粗了
Look at your hands, so rough
阿爹
Dad!
快点盖好被
Put the blanket on
阿爹唱了一辈子戏
I have performed for my whole life
妳看，连头发都白了
Look, I've so much grey hair
想不到妳也要唱戏
Didn't expect you want to act too
阿爹
Dad!
女儿，妳看，妳不去唱戏太可惜了
That'll be a waste if you don't act
对，我最喜欢唱戏你是知道的
You know I like acting
知道，阿爹知道的
Yes, I know
阿爹
Dad!
女儿
Good girl!
阿爹
Dad!
女儿
Daughter!
阿爹呀
Dad!
阿爹，我好难过呀
Dad, I feel so bad!
怎么妳打呵欠每次都不同的？
You yawn differently each time?
妳养足精神，督军今晚要看妳唱戏
Have a good rest
督军来看我唱戏？
He's coming to see me?
对，不过还要找
Right,
昨晚上跟妳一起唱戏的女孩子
also the girl last night
要到哪儿去找呢？
Where can we find her?
怎么妳会突然出现的？
How come you are here?
你不是要找我吗？
Are you looking for me?
刚才怎么没看见妳？
I didn't see you just now?
阿爹
Dad!
反正你已经见到她了，你快点出去吧
You saw her already,
我们要洗脸练功
show your face!
今天晚上要唱一台好戏
We'll be on stage tonight
妳怎么穿成这样？
Why do you dress up like this?
好险呀
Danger!
妳今天晚上真的要唱戏了
You really have to perform tonight
我有办法    什么办法？
- I've a way. - What?
我今天真的要做戏呀？
I've to act tonight?
是呀
Yes!
捧头，踢腿，转身
Do it
好辛苦，我不练罢
It's too hard, I don't want to do it
继续，捧头，踢腿，转身
Continue
你是说叫湘红色诱我爸爸？
You mean Sheung Hung seducing my dad?
什么？叫我色诱她爸爸？
What? Ask me to seduce her dad?
还要我跟妳爸爸过夜呀？
And stay for a night with your dad?
只有这样才能令我爸爸脱军服
That's the only to take off your dad's coat
那条钥匙在军服里边
The key is in the coat
那也就是说要我嫁妳爸爸啰
That means I've to get married to your dad
妳不是要叫我做妈妈？
And you'll call me mom?
到时候妳就把这包迷药
You put this powder
放在他的酒杯里
in his drink
半个时辰他就会醒过来
He'll wake up in 1/2 hours
而曹云她就在房间外面接应妳
She'll take you outside the door
为什么我要帮你们呢？
Why am I helping you for?
先给妳一半
Give me this first
事成之后，再给妳另外的一半
Will pay you the balance afterward
为什么找我不找白妞呢？
Why not Pat Neil?
因为我们知道
Because you won't
只有妳才不会抗拒这样东西
- resist on this
对呀
- Right
什么东西？
What?
没什么
Nothing!
湘红、白妞，出场了
Sheung Hung, Pat Neil, your turn
快点
Quick!
白妞、湘红
Pat Neil, Sheung Hung
恭喜妳第一次正式上台
Congratulation for your debut
谢谢你
Thanks!
祝妳成功
Toss for your success
后台这么危险，你不怕被发现吗？
It's so danger here, you'll get caught?
我想来见妳最后一面
I want to you the last time
最后一面？
Last time?
如果任务成功了
After the mission
妳会留下来还是跟我们走呢？
Will you stay or go with us?
好，那我们再见
See you again
妳是不是担心妳爸爸？
Are you worrying your dad?
他是我唯一的亲人
He's my only relative
妳这样做，如果他发现
If he finds out you do all these
他会不会原谅妳呢？
Will he forgive you?
不会
No!
可能会呢？
May be!
肯定不会
Absolutely not
因为我是他最信任的人
He trusts me the most
督军今晚专诚请两位去喝酒谈心
The General invites you for a drink
怎么妳也要去呀？
You've to go too?
这有什么奇怪，女人一出来抛头露面
What's wrong, once a woman starts working
就会有这种朝烦
They all have this problem
要是妳们不去，戏班就要完了
If you don't go, we'll be finished
那妳怎么办？
What are you going to do?
我去找宁先生商量
I go to fetch Mr. Ling
他一定有办法应付的
He can think for something
我的药呢？不好了
Where is the powder!
不用找了，再拿一包吧
No need to find, take another one
千万别禽了，否则今晚回不来了
Don't lose it, if not, don't come back
你真是太好了，告诉你一件事
You're terrific, tell you something
那天在大帅府，打晕了你那个是…
That day in General's house, someone hit you...
不用说了
Don't say it
我早知道是妳干的
I knew is you
真不好意思
I don't mean it
妳打得不太重
You hit it so hard
没关系…
It doesn't matter
半个时辰…
1/2 hours. . .
督军到
General's here
今天两位的表演真是精已绝伦
You two perform
空前绝后
excellent
怎么不坐呀？
Why don't you sit down?
督军呀，你看我的手
Look at my hands
妳的手？没什么嘛
Your hands? Nothing
那一只呢，也没什么呀
Another one, nothing too
督军，你看清楚一点
See more clearly
没什么嘛
Nothing
两手空空的，是不是应该戴点戒指呀
Do you think, it'll look better with rings
手镯呀，钻石呀，对不对？
Bracelets, diamond, right?
妳这么贪钱，真叫人疼妳
You're so greedy and lovely
让我看看妳的手又有些什么
Let me see your hands too
抓着拳头干什么？
Why are holding your palms?
让我看看…
Let me see...
不错嘛
Not bad
现在轮到这一只，让我看看…
Another one, let me see. . .
不要紧张，放松点
Relax. . .
干什么？
- What for?
督军呀
- General!
妳干什么？
What are you doing?
督军，我们来玩一个游戏吧
Let have a game
玩什么游戏？
What game?
你猜猜
Just guest
我猜，有什么好猜的
Guest?
到底玩什么？
Tell me!
玩完了
It's finished
耍我？
Fool me?
我要罚妳喝酒
You're punished to drink
我不能喝
I don't know drinking
不能喝也要喝
You've to drink
拿着
Hold it!
不要呀
Don't!
喝
Drink!
我罚妳喝光它…
You've to finish it. . .
为什么把我爸爸搞成这样？
What did you do to my dad?
我只是轻轻的打他
I only hit him slightly
不要吵醒他
Don't wake him up
怎么没有呢？
How come?
是不是这个？
Is it this one?
妳在哪里找到的？
Where did you get it?
在他的口袋里
In his pocket
妳打开过？
You opened it?
是不是这个呀？
Is it this one?
不错，就是这个
Yes, it is
把暗格打开
Open it
这是妳另外一半的酬金
This is your balance payment
就这一点呀？
That's it?
什么意思？
What do you mean?
你们的计划本来是失败了
You'll fail
要不是我随机应变
If I don't have a quick mind
你们根本就拿不到这份文件
You wouldn't get this papers
那我是不是应该多要一点呢
So I should have more
文件已经在我手里
I got the papers already
妳想多要一点也不可能了
You won't get more
大概妳不知道
You didn't know that
在偷文件的时候，我撕了一半下来
When I stole those papers, I kept 1/2
这一半还在我这里
They are with me
交出来
Hand it out!
不交
No!
交出来
Hand it out!
妳不敢开枪的
You wouldn't shoot me
白妞跟我拿性命去换来的
Pat Neil and I take this with our lifes
妳还要给钱她呢
You've to pay her too
还胡说八道
Don't be silly
一个要文件，不择手段
One is for the paper by all means
一个贪钱，不知廉耻
One is for money without shame
妳们俩都出卖下友
Both of you betray your friend
我不想再看见妳们
I don't want to see you again
白妞
Pat Neil!
不要拉住我
Don't pull me
妳叫我们去喝酒
You asked us for a drink
是想我引诱妳爸爸
Because you wanted me to seduce your dad
我不是这个意思
I didn't mean that
妳这样对待妳爸爸
You treat your dad that way
这样对待下友，妳还算是人吗？
And your friend too, do you have conscience?
我这样做不是为了我自己一个人
I'm not doing this for myself
妳有没有想过，妳爸爸不会放过我
Did you know that your dad will not let you off?
那我以后怎么办呢？
What am I going to do?
救命呀
Help!
放了她
Release her
湘红，不用怕，没事了
Sheung Hung, you'll be alright
妳不用害怕，没事了
Don't be afraid
原来他是邝查处的人
He's from the Ticketing Office
他注意了我们这么久
He stared at us for a long time
我的身份岂不是暴露了
I'll expose my identity
阿爹…
Dad. . .
不要吵，进去吧
Come in silently
过来，白妞呀
That's Pat Neil
白妞
- Pat Neil!
金爷
- Mr.Kam
妳爹跟那些花旦全给督军抓走了
Your dad and the actors are imprisoned
什么？
What?
现在督军到处在找妳跟湘红俩
The General is looking for you and Sheung Hung
那怎么办？
What are we going to do
妳快走吧
Run!
我们到哪儿去呢？
Where are we going?
去南京
Naking!
我们的人会接应妳们
Our men will meet you there
快点，走呀
Run!
那我爹呢？
How about my dad?
妳不用担心，曹云她会救妳爹的
Don't worry, Tsao Wan will save your dad
妳走呀
Go!
走呀…快点呀
Quick!
这边
This way!
湘红，妳怎么回来这儿？
Sheung Hung, how come you're back?
曹云叫我把这份东西交给你
Tsao Wan asked me to give you this
她自己呢？
Where is she?
她说她的身份可能暴露了
She said her identity was exposed
所以要回到她爸爸身边
So she has to go back to her dad's
必要时她会作最后的牺牲
She'll sacrified
什么？
What?
你们到处搜清楚
Search all around
看看还有没有人
See if there anyone?
是
Yes!
到那边去看看
Go over that side
你们不要出去
Don't come out!
不要出去，好危险呀
It's dangerous
保护文件
Take care this paper
我挡着，你们快走
You go first
走呀
Go!
不要去呀
Don't!
快走呀，走呀…白妞
Pat Neil, run!
别让他们跑了，快追
Don't let them run away, chase them!
追
Chase!
分头包抄
Go separately!
快些，追
Quick
你们俩到那边去搜
- You two go over that way
是
- Yes
这样下去不是办法
That's not a way
保护文件
Take care the paper
我去引开他们
I lead them away
喂
Hai!
快走
Run!
你们往那边看，其余的跟我走  是
You stay here, others follow me
在前面
Over there
走
Run!
不要动…
Freeze. . .
再动我就枪毙你
If not, I'll shoot you
怎么办呢？
What are we going to do?
不要怕，我一定想办法救他们
Don't scare, I'll find a way to save them
现在我们已经证实曹云的身份
We've proof for Tsao's identity
抓不抓她呢？
Did you get her?
我们怎么应付督军呢？
How are we going to handle General?
谁？
Who?
爸爸
Dad!
快去收拾一下
Pack up
我们今晚带领人马离开这儿
We all have to go tonight
你在这么仓猝的时间带这么多人走
If you go away with all these people
会惊动其他的军队
It's too obvious
很容易被误会而打起来
And will start a fight
爸爸禽了很重要的东西，不走不行呀
Dad lost an important matter, he needs to go
这更危险了
That's too serious
你的下属知道你失势了，一定会造反
If your subordinates know you lose you power, there'll be a riot
我看我们两父女乔装偷走
It's saver
反而会更安全呢
if you disguise
什么安全？
What?
如果我怕危险的话，就不会当军人
If I afraid of dangerous, I'll not be an army
我用性命来拼了这么多年
I fought with my life for years
谁敢动我就打谁
Kill those who are supporting me
爸爸，你不要只顾着自己
Dad, think of the others
你该顾全大局呀
Think for the whole situation
大局…没有我还讲什么大局
Talking about the situation without me
话说得挺漂亮
Sweet talking
其实每个人都是为了自己
All people are selfish
权力越大就势力越大了
Talk louder with bigger power
爸爸
Dad!
Dad,
如果每一个做官的都是你这种想法
if you council think that way
那我们还要政府来干什么？
Why we need the government?
我就是这样，谁不服从我就枪毙谁
That's me, shoot those not agree with me
爸爸
Dad!
不顶怎么样
No matter what's happening,
我们两父女还是要在一起
we'll be together
快去收拾东西吧，时间不多了
Pack up, time is running short
好，我去了
Alright I'll go!
把钥匙给我，你们俩出去吧
Give me the key, you two get out!
是
Yes!
快点走呀，否则来不及了
Quick, if not, it'll be too late
我们有救了，快走呀…
We got help...run. . .
真的劫后余生
We're save
逃出生天
Yes
还唱什么
Stop singing,
再唱我就推你回牢里去
if not, I put you in jail again
走开呀
Get away!
他为什么都跑了
What are they running!
快点
Quick!
快点罢
Run!
停不下来
Can't take a break
爸爸
Dad!
妳的行李呢？
Where is your luggages!
还没收拾呢
Not pack yet
不用收拾了，走吧
Let's go without it!
报告    什么事？
- Report! - Yes?
邝查处的人来了
The Ticketing Officers are here
邝查处算是什么东西？
Who do you think they are?
你进来干什么？走
Who are you here? Go!
我们想邀请妳女儿回去
We want to invite your daughter to our office
因为我们怀疑你女儿勾结乱党
As we suspect her has connection with the guerillas
你们这些兔崽子
You have no right
有什么资格在这里说话
to say so
乱党，我女儿不是乱党
My daughter is not a guerillas
谁敢胡说八道我就杀了他
Anyone says that, I'll kill him
爸爸…
Dad. . .
爸爸
我女儿不是乱党，她绝对不是乱党
She's not a guerillas
阿云，妳走，走呀
Wan, run...
把枪拾起来
Hide up the gun
这个姓段的将军中饱私囊，逃亡走了
General Tun run away with everything
怎么现在又回来了？
How come he's back?
对呀，这些政治问题，我也不大懂
I don't understand politics
以前姓曹的得势
Before, Tsao used to have the power
姓段的就要逃亡了
Then Tun had to run away
现在姓曹的失势了
Now Tsao was collapsed
姓段的当然回来了
Tun is back
这么简单的事也不懂
That's simple
你说什么？
What did you say?
时事顶坛呀
Social talking!
时事顶坛？抓回去下刑落口供
Take him back?
我是归国华侨呀
I'm an oversea Chinese
更朝烦了，用外汇，罪名更大
Even worse
抓回去
Knock him up
沙来了，组长
Sand! Captain!
文件呢？
Where's the document?
我吞下肚子里了
I swallow it
在妳的肚子里面？
In your stomach?
继续打
Hit!
盐水
Salt water!
好了，不要再玩了
Please stop
否则我就不客气了
If not, I'll lose my temper
等等
Wait!
我想试试姓曹的女儿，你帮帮忙吧
Would you help me to test Tsao's daughter
等我试完后，任你处置好了
You can do what you like after that
好，送她去将军府
OK, send her to General's house
曹云…
Tsao Wan...
你们俩太寂寞了
You feel lonely
天黑以前处决他们
Sentenced them at night
是
Yes!
报告将军，有人求见
Report, someone wants to see you
由现在开始到明天早上
I don't see anyone from now
我不接见任何人
till tomorrow morning
谁要见我的就枪毙谁
Shoot him if he insist
将军…
General!...
原来是妳
Oh, is you?
将军，她找得你好苦呀
General, she's looking for you so badly
她有病也要来找你
Even she's sick
你看她多可怜呀
So touching
为什么你们不报告？
Why don't you tell me that?
将军，小人已经向你报告了
I did
扶她上书房
Take her to study room
你可以出去了
You can go
在外边等我
Wait me outside
不要骚扰我，否则我枪毙你
Don't bother me, if not, I'll shoot you
我在哪儿呀？
Where am I?
将军，原来是你
Oh, is you, General?
就是我，妳刚才晕倒了
You passed out just now
怪不得我心跳得这么厉害
My heart is beating so fast
不信你听听
You don't believe me, listen
我来听听…
Listen!
妳干什么？
What are you doing?
将军呀
General!
妳别那么心急嘛
Be patient
来呀…
Come...
让我亲一下
- Give me a kiss
你别心急呀
- Be patient
别动
Hold it!
这个时候妳还跟我开玩笑
Don't fool me
来呀…
Come...
不要走…
Don't go! . . .
回来…
Come back...
不要走呀…回来…
Don't go . . . come back. . .
过来…
Come back...
别动
Hold it!
妳别再耍我了，我才不信妳
I don't trust you
干什么？
What are you doing?
将军，什么事？
General?
有什么事呀？将军
What's happening?
将军…
General...
不要呀
Don't
将军呀，你没叫他们，他们全进来了
General, they come in without your permission
还不出去？
Get out?
顺便叫我的姐妹进来
Lead my sister to come in
将军请妳进去呀
General ask you to go in
快点关门呀
Close the door!
湘红
Sheung Hung!
曹云，怎么妳也在这里？
Tsao Wan, how come you are here too?
小声点
Keep quiet!
坐下来再说
Sit down first
妳怎么哭了？
Why are crying?
是谁把妳打成这样？
Who beat you?
妳告诉我，到底是谁？
Tell me, who?
我没事，妳不用担心
I'm fine, don't worry
天黑了，他们就要处决北海跟董民
They'll kill Pak Hoi and Tung Man tonight
太阳快要下山了，怎么办？
The sun is setting, what can we do?
快点想办法救他们
Find a way to save them
看见对面大楼最高的窗吗？
Did you see the window of the tallest bidg?
他们就关在那里
He's being knocked in there
白妞，妳可以爬到对面大楼吗？
Pat Neil, do you think you can climb up there?
我想办法
I'm looking for a way
快去拿将军的枪
Go and get General's pistol
不要晕呀
Faded!
白妞，他们俩的性命，就在妳的手里
Their lives are in your hand
妳一定要成功，去吧
You've to success
小心呀
- Go - Be careful
来，快点把床单驳起来
Tide up the bed sheet
驳床单？
Tide it up?
爬下去呀
Climb down!
快点呀，来呀
Quick!
开门
Open the door!
乱党宁北海、董民，阴谋叛国
Patriotic Ling and Tung intimate to start a riot
判以死刑
Were sentenced death
命令就地处决
Immediately
准备行刑，瞄准，开
Ready. . . Fire!
你们怎么了？
How are you?
行了
OK!
快点拿钥匙
Take the key
那些刑兵怎么了？休息呀
How about the soldier? Take a rest!
走
Go!
到那边看看有什么事？
Go over that side?
车房在那边
The garage is over there
快点呀
Quick!
北京填鸭
Peking Duck!
北京填鸭在这里呀
Peking Duck is here
北海、曹云
Pak Hoi, Tsao Wan!
董民、湘红
Tung Man, Sheung Hung!
你们没事吧？
Are you OK?
没事
I'm fine
白妞，妳没事吧？
Pat Neil?
我们出去了再拥抱吧
Let's hug outside!
快点上车
Get in the car
排长
Captain!
准备换班
Changing time
乱党，追…
Patriotic, chase...
文件在哪里？
Where's the document?
在戏院，我们要回去拿
In the theatre, let go back and get it
是不是有人偷懒呀？
Is there any being lazy?
怎么老是演忠的人不够呢？
How come there's so little good guy?
快点出来呀
Get out!
金爷
Mr Kam!
白妞
Pat Neil!
我爹呢？
Where dad?
江老板…
Mr Wong. . .
白妞，妳回来了
Pat Neil, you're back
阿爹
Dad!
妳没什么吧？
Are you alright?
没什么
I'm fine!
我们回来拿点东西，马上要走了
We're back for something, and will leave soon
今晚就走了
We're leaving tonight
组长，车子在这里
Captain, the car is ready
他们一定躲在这里附近
They must hide somewhere around
回去派大批军队来
- Send a team here
是
- Yes!
跟我来
Follow me!
封锁这几条街，立即戒严
Block the street
外面戒严了，坐下
Sit down
继续看戏
Continue!
封锁出路，搜查戏院
Search the theatre
是
Yes!
他们好像知道我们在这里
They know we are here
我们快从后门走吧
Get out at the back door
整间戏院都封锁了
The theatre's being surrounding
全部出口都封锁了？
They block all exits
有办法，今晚演八仙过海
I've a way, tonight we perform the 8 fairies
我们化妆出场
We'll on stage
你们出场？
You?
胡子掉了
The moustache's down
前后台都没有？
Can't find them anywhere?
过来
Come over!
我们的计划是从屋顶走
We get out from the roof
什么时候走呀？
When?
记住，暗号是嘲江倒海
The code is collapse
组长，人都到齐了
Captain, all men are here
紧守岗位，要一网打尽
In position
是
Yes!
今晚我要一只苍蝇也飞不掉
I want all of them
我的壳还没脱掉呀
I can't take of my shell
八仙过海，为什么海鲜都上天？捉人
Why they are going up? Catch them!
嘲江倒海
Collapse
我害怕
I'm afraid.
快点
Quick!
救命呀
Help!
不用怕
Don't be afraid
别吵，下面全是他们的人
Keep quiet, they're just down there
快点起来呀
Get up quick
快伏下
Lie down!
妳没事吧？
Are you alright?
不要紧，我的肩膀受伤了
Doesn't matter, my shoulder is hurt
小心他们开枪
Be careful
小心，组长
Beware, Captain!
你们走呀，再见
Bye!
曹云
Tsao Wan!
曹云姐
Wan!
他妈的
Shit!
挡子弹
The bullet
瞄得真准
Good shot
上去呀
Go up!
在那边
That way!
曹云
Tsao Wan!
是雷组长呀？
Is Commander Liu?
是谁开的枪？
Who is shooting?
没有呀
No one!
一定是乱党，追…
Must be the patriotic! . . .
我们现在去南方政府
We'll go South,
把文件交给国会
to hand this paper to the congress
等国会讨伐袁世凯
Let them to handle Yuen
那我们就在这里分手吧
We see you off here!
你们打算到哪里去？
Where are you going?
我去天津找我爹，然后再跑江湖
I'll keep singing
我唯有再卖唱
Leave China when I've enough money
凑够了钱就离开中国
But it's so turbulent
现在天下这么乱
Then I'll go hometown, first
我只有回乡下去耕田，避一避再说
Don't feel sad
不要这么难过
We'll see again
天下这么大，我们一定有机会再见的
I'll fetch my dad in Tinjuin
民主成功之后，在北平再见吧
After the revolution, meet you in Peking
好，我们再见
See you then
那我们大家要珍重
Take care
好
OK